So I'm back in our finished project, basically in the same state as we had once we deployed it
yleyse bitirdiimiz projemize geri dndmde, bir zamanlar biz de onun yerine yerletirdiimiz gibi
and there, obviously if we run our application it looks like this.
ayn durumdayz, akas eer uygulamamz yrtrsek, buna benziyor.
We have our burger builder,
Bizim burger oluturucu var,
we can authenticate through firebase
biz sadece bizim kimlik bilgilerini girerek giri
so by simply entering our credentials, logging in and then we can start building the burger as we always
yaptktan sonra firebase zerinden kimlik dorulamas yapabiliriz ve sonra bu kurs boyunca
did it throughout this course
her zaman yaptmz gibi
so nothing spectacular here.
burger ina etmeye balayabiliriz.
If we have a look at the code which should be familiar to you,
Size aina olmas gereken bir koda
we handle all these asynchronous tasks or actually any side effects, even synchronous ones,
bakacak olursak, tm bu ezamansz grevleri veya aslnda herhangi bir yan etkiyi,
so things that are not directly related to changing our redux store, we handle all these things in action
hatta senkronize olanlar, yani redux maazamz deitirmeyle ilgili olmayan eyleri ele alyoruz.
creators.
Aksiyon yaratclar
So here I'm in the auth actions file where I have all auth related action creators,
te burada, tm auth ile ilgili aksiyon oluturucularn olduu auth eylemleri dosyamdaym,
we got a couple of synchronous ones here
burada bir ift ezamanl
but then we also have things like accessing local store and should log out which is a synchronous action
var, ama o zaman yerel maazaya erimek gibi eyler de var ve size
I will give you that but which you could argue
vereceim senkronize bir eylemden k yapmalyz. Bu
and again, that's not necessarily a best practice but you could argue that this is not really related
ama yine de tartabilecein, bu mutlaka en iyi uygulama deil, bunun bir eylem
to the act of dispatching an action
gnderme eylemiyle gerekten ilgili olmadn,
so maybe you don't want to have it in this file. And we also have asynchronous actions like checkoff
belki de bu dosyaya sahip olmak istemediini syleyebilirsin. Ayrca, belirlediimiz zaman amna sahip olduumuz ve belirli bir geerlilik sresinden
timeout where we have a timeout we set and where we then dispatch log out after a certain expiration time. And
sonra k yapmamz gereken zaman am gibi ezamansz eylemlerimiz de var. Webe ularz, posta talepleri
we reach out to the web,
yaparz
we make post requests and obviously we have to wait for these to finish.
ve akas bunlarn bitmesini beklemek zorundayz.
So all these are things which we have in the action creators
Bu yzden tm bunlar, eylem yaratclarnda sahip olduumuz
and as I said multiple times, that's not necessarily bad
eylerdir ve birok kez sylediim gibi,
but you could make the argument that you want action creators or the whole idea of dispatching actions
bu kesinlikle kt deildir, ancak eylem yaratclarnn veya eylemlerin ok temiz olmas iin tm eylem
to be very clean, that you don't want to have any other code in there which is not really related to dispatching
fikrini istemediinizi iddia edebilirsiniz. Orada bir eylem gnderilmesiyle gerekten ilgili olmayan baka bir kodun olmasn istiyorum
an action and this is where redux saga comes in.
ve bu da redux destannn geldii yer.
So first of all let's install it so that we can see how it works,
Her eyden nce, nasl altn grebilmemiz iin onu
So I will run npm install --save and that it's redux-saga,
ykleyelim, bu yzden npm install --save' altryorum ve bu redux-destan, paket
that's the package name and this will as always download it,
ad ve bu her zaman olduu gibi
place an entry in the package.json file and then give us access to it in this project and I will
indirecek, pakete bir giri koyacaktr. . json dosyas ve daha sonra bu projede ona eriim
restart the development server with npm start again.
verin ve npm ile yeniden balatma sunucusunu yeniden balatacam.
Now we can start working on the project and we can start using redux saga,
Artk projede almaya balayabiliriz ve redux destann kullanmaya balayabiliriz, bunu
let's do this beginning in the next video.
bir sonraki videoda balayalm.